沼泽不是沼泽。
Marsh is not swamp.
沼泽是一片光明的空间。
Marsh is a space of light...
那里的草长在水里。
where grass grows in water...
水流入天空。
and water flows into the sky.
然后在沼泽里，到处都是..。
Then within the marsh, here and there...
真正的沼泽。
true swamp.
沼泽知道死亡的一切。
A swamp knows all about death...
并不一定定义为悲剧。
and doesn't necessarily
define it as tragedy.
当然不是罪过。
Certainly not a sin.
我以为蔡斯 · 安德鲁斯会更有常识。
I thought Chase Andrews
would have more common sense.
这个镇上最好的四分卫。
Best quarterback this town ever had.
孩子们，这是你们的脚印吗？
Boys, are these your footprints here?
是的，长官。
Yes, sir.
他的脚印呢？
Where's his footprints?
是啊，有些孩子只是脑子里有些疯狂的想法
Yeah, some kids
just get crazy ideas in their heads
喝酒，认为他们是不可战胜的。
and drink and think they're invincible.
Chase Andrews 不是小孩。
That Chase Andrews was no Kid.
嘿，看看这个。
Hey. Look at this.
- 他自己打开的?-可能是意外。
- He open the grate himself?
- Could've been an accident, all the same.
死亡时间，午夜到凌晨两点之间。
Time of death,
between midnight and 2 a.m.
死因是从63英尺高空坠落造成的突然撞击。
Cause of death,
sudden impact from the 63-foot drop.
既然你在支撑梁上发现了血迹和头发,
Since you found that blood
and hair on the support beam,
我可以推断这就是原发伤的原因。
I would deduce that was
the cause of the primary injury.
用外行人的话说，他下来的时候撞到了后脑勺。
Laymen's terms, he banged
the back of his head on the way down.
把他的后脑勺撞到横梁上,
To hit the back of his head on the beam,
他就得往后倒，对吗？
he would've needed
to fall backwards, is that right?
- 是的-所以他可能是被推下去的。
- I'd say yes.
- So he might have been pushed.
栏杆和栅栏上都没有指纹，什么都没有。
There's no fingerprints on the railing,
the grates, nothing.
没有指纹? Chase 也没有？
No fingerprints? Not from Chase either?
没有指纹，没有痕迹。
No fingerprints, no tracks.
我们在夹克上发现了红色纤维。
We do have those red fibers
found on the jacket.
我刚从亚特兰大拿到实验室报告。
I just got the lab report
back from Atlanta.
不是他其他衣服上的。
They did not come
from any of his other clothing.
上面说是羊毛，可能是毛衣，围巾。
Wool, it says.
That could be a sweater, scarf.
什么都有可能。
Hell, it could be anything.
我们得找到它。
And we gotta find it.
美丽的妻子，温馨的家庭，想不到有谁会想杀 Chase。
A beautiful wife, good family. Can't think
of anyone who'd want to kill Chase.
拜托，你知道蔡斯的为人。
Come on. You know how Chase was.
像被关起来的公牛一样发情。
Tomcattin', ruttin' around
like a penned-up bull let out.
别说死人的坏话，弗兰克。
Don't speak ill of the dead, Frank.
我只是说我能想到几个人来做。
I'm just saying
I could think of a few guys up to it.
- 弥尔顿先生-嗨，桑迪。
- Mr. Milton.
- Hi, Sandy.
- 老样子? 不伦瑞克炖肉?-你怎么猜到的。
- The usual? Brunswick stew?
- How'd you guess.
你对 Chase Andrews 的案子有什么看法 Tom？
What do you make
of the Chase Andrews case, Tom?
我退休了，这不关我的事。
Oh, I'm retired.
That's none of my business anymore.
- 有道理-可能是沼泽里的那个女人。
- Fair enough.
- Could've been that woman in the marsh.
她已经够疯狂的了，我打赌她会做这样的事。
She's crazy enough for the loony bin.
I bet she'd be up to something like this.
我哥哥告诉我沼泽女孩是缺失的一环。
My brother's told me
that Marsh Girl's the missing link.
你知道可怜的蔡斯 · 安德鲁斯在那片沼泽地里发生了什么事。
You know poor Chase Andrews had
something going on down in that marsh.
Chase Andrews 和沼泽女孩? 如果这不是自找麻烦的话。
Chase Andrews and the Marsh Girl?
Now if that ain't asking for trouble.
你觉得到底发生了什么，弗兰克？
What do you think
really happened, Frank?
你觉得是沼泽女孩杀了 Chase？
You think that Marsh Girl killed Chase?
我不知道，真相总会大白的。
Hell, I don't know.
Truth will come out.
看看这些羽毛什么的。
Look at all these feathers and whatnot.
她是科学家还是女巫？
She a scientist or a witch?
克拉克小姐？
Miss Clark?
- 警长办公室-警长。
- Sheriff's Department.
- Sheriff.
你看。
Look.
可以申请搜查令。
Could get a warrant.
视野开阔，正当理由，警长。
Plain view. Probable cause, sheriff.
我打赌那门根本没锁。
Bet that door isn't even locked.
她来了。
There she is.
这里是警察局，关掉引擎。
This is the Sheriff's Department.
Shut down your engine.
直走，直走，跟着她！
Go straight, go straight. Follow her in!
- 你有罪!-你杀了 Chase Andrews！
- You're guilty!
- You killed Chase Andrews!
- 你会为此付出代价的!-烂在监狱里！
- You'll pay for this!
- Rot in jail!
主日正义，你去哪了 Kitty？
Sunday Justice.
Where you gone, kitty?
请留下来。
Please stay.
过来，猫咪，猫咪。
Here, kitty, kitty.
克拉克小姐？
Miss Clark?
我是汤姆 · 米尔顿。
I'm Tom Milton.
我是律师，我能进来吗？
I'm a lawyer. May I come in?
谢谢，弗雷泽先生。
Thank you, Mr. Frazier.
你可能知道你因为谋杀 Chase Andrews 被拘留了。
You probably know that you're being held
for the murder of Chase Andrews.
我冒昧地站出来为你辩护。
And I have taken the liberty of putting
myself forward to defend you.
我知道你以前从没惹过麻烦,
I know you've never been
in trouble before,
这样我就能解释法庭和审判，以及谁是谁什么的。
so I can explain the courtroom
and the trial and who is who and whatnot.
你有家人愿意和你一起去吗？
Uh, do you have family
that you might want to come be with you?
克拉克小姐，我不知道该怎么说，但是..。
Miss Clark, I don't quite know
how to put this, but, uh...
我知道你是凯瑟琳 · 丹妮尔 · 克拉克,
Well, I know you
as Catherine Danielle Clark,
但在 Barkley Cove 他们不这么叫你。
but here in Barkley Cove
they don't call you by that name.
他们叫你沼泽女孩。
They call you Marsh Girl.
当你受审时,
And when you stand trial,
你们将由陪审团审判
you will be judged by a jury of your peers
来自巴克利湾，只知道你是这样的人。
from Barkley Cove,
who only know you as such.
不管他们认不认识你，他们都会对你评头论足。
They are going to judge you
whether they know you or not.
但除非我认识你，否则我帮不了你。
But I can't help you unless I know you.
哪怕只有一点点。
Even just a little bit.
那好吧。
Well, all right, then. Um...
等你有时间考虑之后，我再回来。
I'll come back in a while
when you've had time to consider.
我还给你带了这个。
Oh, and I brought you this
just in the meantime.
弗雷泽先生。
Mr. Frazier.
人们忘记了生活在贝壳里的生物。
People forget about the creatures
who live in shells.
我曾经有过一个家庭。
I had a family once.
他们叫我 Kya。
They called me Kya.
Kya！
Kya!
Kya! 你最好别跑太远。
Kya! You'd better not get too far out.
抓住它，抓住它！
Get it, get it!
现在这只小猪去市场了，你别动。
Now this little piggy went
to market. Now you hold still.
这只小猪呆在家里。
This little piggy stayed home.
这只小猪吃了烤牛肉。
This little piggy ate roast beef.
这只小猪没有。
This little piggy had none.
这只小猪一路上都在嘘嘘嘘嘘。
And this little piggy went
wee-wee-wee-wee all the way home.
这才是我的宝贝女儿。
That's my special girl.
嘿 Jodie！
Hey, Jodie!
塔特！
Hey, Tate!
想来钓鱼吗？
Wanna come fishing?
- 我没有太多时间-“没有”不是一个真正的词。
- I ain't got too much time.
- "Ain't" isn't a real word.
嘿，我跟你说过多少次了，别在我的船上捣乱！
Hey, how many times I told you
not to mess in my goddamn boat?!
进屋去，你傻了吗！
Get in the house! Are you stupid?!
过来! 现在你做到了。
Come here! Now you've done it.
你得学会尊重，听到了吗？
You gotta learn respect. You hear me?
- 住手! 你弄疼她了!-嘿，放开我爸爸！
- Stop it! You're hurting her!
- Hey, you leave my pa alone!
回到我的地盘，我会开枪的，听到了吗！
Come back on my land,
I'll shoot you! You hear me?!
- 冷静点-闭嘴！
- Calm down now.
- Shut up!
闭嘴！
Shut up!
- 放开我!-我让你看看！
- Leave me alone!
- I'll show you!
求你别说了！
Please just stop!
妈！
Ma!
妈？
Ma?
妈妈再也没回来。
Ma never came back.
其他人也很快以同样的方式离开。
And everybody else was quick
to get out the same way.
墨菲是第一个离开的。
Murph was the first to leave.
几个月后 Mandy 和 Missy。
A few months later, Mandy and Missy.
最后，朱迪。
Then, finally, Jodie.
Kya.
Kya，听着。
Kya, listen.
我得走了，Kya，我不能再住在这里了。
I have to go, Kya.
I can't live here no longer.
Kya，你要小心，听到了吗？
Kya, you be careful, hear?
如果你有麻烦,
If you're in trouble,
跑到沼泽深处，躲到小龙唱歌的地方。
run and hide deep in the marsh
way out where the crawdads sing.
就像妈妈常说的。
Like Ma always says.
快跑！
Run!
朱迪！
Jodie!
我从其他人的错误中学会了如何和他一起生活。
I learned from the mistakes
of the others how to live with him.
别挡道。
Just keep out of the way.
别让他看见你。
Don't let him see you.
照顾好自己。
Fend for yourself.
我和朱迪去过很多次沼泽地，但从来没有一个人去过。
I had been out in the marsh plenty
of times with Jodie, but never alone.
我不知道哪边是家。
I didn't know which way was home.
该死的，你把我留在这里，朱迪！
Damn you for leaving me here, Jodie!
去你的。
Damn you.
你没事吧？
You okay?
你是 Jodie Clark 的妹妹。
You're Jodie Clark's sister.
曾经是，他走了。
Used to be. He's gone.
- 你知道回家的路吗?-知道。
- You know your way home?
- Yeah.
没关系，我总是迷路。
It's okay. I get lost all the time.
我叫塔特，以防你再见到我。
My name's Tate, in case you see me again.
塔特。
Tate.
那个男孩身上有某种东西缓解了我胸口的紧张。
There was something about that boy
that eased the tightness in my chest.
妈妈和朱迪离开后第一次,
For the first time
since Ma and Jodie left,
除了受伤，我还有别的感觉。
I felt something other than hurt.
我觉得自己很勇敢。
I felt brave.
肚子好饿啊。
I'm hungry.
早上好，克拉克先生，你好吗？
Morning, Mr. Clark. How you doing?
跳啊，我醒来时发现自己在泥土的右边。
Well, Jumpin',
I woke up on the right side of dirt.
这是我女儿 Kya Clark 小姐。
Oh, this is my daughter, Miss Kya Clark.
我很荣幸认识你，Kya 小姐。
Well, I'm mighty proud
to know you, Miss Kya.
哦，别介意，我告诉她，离所有人远点。
Oh, don't mind her.
I tell her, uh, stay away from everybody.
- 这是个危险的世界，不是吗?-是的，但是钓鱼是好事。
- It's a dangerous world, isn't it?
- It is. But the fishing's good.
能给我一包燕麦吗？
Could I get a bag of grits?
再来点金边威士忌？
And some of that Jim Beam?
- 也许你可以帮我加满-没关系。
- And maybe you fill her up for me?
- It's okay.
- 梅宝-嗯哼。
- Mabel.
- Mm-hm.
等我们找钱，听到了吗？
You wait for our change, you hear?
在你妈妈不在的时候帮助你爸爸，是吗？
Helping out your pa
while your ma's gone, huh?
我有段时间没见到她了。
I ain't seen her in a while.
- 她在家做家务-他。
- She's doing chores at home.
- Mm-him.
没什么线索。
Grits ain't much to go on.
好吧，让我看看。
All right. Let's see here.
你爸留了两块钱在这里。
Your pa left $2 here.
账单是1.5美元。
And the bill is $1.50.
还剩多少油钱？
How much does that leave for gas?
别担心。
Don't worry about that.
我还有个问题。
I got another question for you.
你在上学吗，亲爱的？
You go to school, honey?
你知道他们在报纸上公布了学校的午餐菜单吗？
Do you know that they publish
the school lunch menu in the paper?
今天是..。
Today's is...
索尔兹伯里牛排。
Salisbury steak.
你可以吃顿热腾腾的饭，交些朋友。
You could get a nice, hot meal,
make some friends.
很多孩子不穿鞋上学。
Plenty of kids go to school without shoes.
但你需要一条裙子。
But you will need a skirt.
问你妈妈要一个。
Ask your mama for one.
这就对了。
There you go.
零钱是50美分。
And the change is 50 cents.
孩子们！
Boys!
蔡斯 · 安德鲁斯，你有什么要说的吗？
Chase Andrews,
what you got to say for yourself?
抱歉，潘茜小姐。
Sorry, Miss Pansy.
我们没看到你，是因为那个女孩挡道了。
We didn't see you
'cause that girl got in the way.
你好啊。
Hello there.
我觉得你转错方向了，小姑娘。
I think you've got yourself
turned around the wrong way, little lady.
学校不是在那边吗？
Isn't school that way?
- 好脏-恶心。
- So dirty.
- Gross.
你也有权去那里。
You have just as much of a right
to be there.
去吧，没事的。
Go along now. It's all right.
凯瑟琳 · 丹妮尔 · 克拉克小姐，你已经开始读写了吗？
Miss Catherine Danielle Clark,
are you reading and writing already?
你会拼“狗”吗，亲爱的？
Can you spell "dog," honey?
那是谁？
Who is that?
天哪。
G-O-D.
我们都需要练习，不是吗？
Well, we can all use practice, can't we?
你可以坐下了 Catherine Danielle Clark 小姐。
You can go ahead and sit down,
Miss Catherine Danielle Clark.
你去哪了 Marsh？
Where you been, marsh hen?
你的帽子呢，臭小子？
Where's your hat, swamp rat?
现在，孩子们，安静下来，还有一个小时就吃午饭了。
Now, boys and girls, settle down.
Just an hour until lunch.
请注意我们的课。
Please, try to pay attention
to our lesson.
谁能告诉我一个发长元音的单词？
Who can tell me a word
that has a long vowel sound?
- 她可能住在泥里-有人长虱子了。
- She probably lives in the mud.
- Someone's got cooties.
房间里那股臭味。
That stink in the room.
不好意思。
Excuse me.
那是我在学校的唯一一天。
That was the only day
I ever spent in school.
我觉得我还是向野外学习比较好。
Reckoned I was better off learning
from the wild.
嗨，塔特！
Hi, Tate!
嗯。
Mm-mm.
你要小心点，听到了吗？
Need you to be careful out here.
You hear me?
你不能相信任何人。
You can't trust nobody.
你要保护好自己。
You protect yourself.
可能是大雕鴞。
Great horned owl, probably.
有一段时间，爸爸对我很好。
For a while, Pa was good to me.
我想你可以用这个做你的羽毛，鸟巢。
Ahem. I thought you could use this
for your feathers, bird nests.
你收集的其他东西。
Other stuff you collect.
- 谢谢-不客气。
- Oh, thank you.
- Yeah.
- 是我以前的军队...-邮件！
- It was my old Army...
- Mail!
这是我的旧军用背包。
It's my old Army knapsack.
是妈妈寄来的，是妈妈寄来的！
It's from Ma! It's from Ma!
这是妈妈的笔迹！
It's Ma's handwriting!
- 妈妈还活着!-给我。
- Ma's alive!
- Give it to me.
给我。
Give it to me.
- 她什么时候回家-等等。
- When's she coming home?
- Wait.
她说什么？
What does she say?
- 不!-安静。
- No!
- Quiet.
爸爸! 爸爸，住手！
Pa! Pa, stop!
住手! 住手！
Stop it! Stop that!
- 住手!-安静，安静！
- Stop!
- Quiet. Quiet!
妈。
Ma.
现在你听我说。
Now you listen to me.
她再也不会回来了。
She ain't never coming back.
听到了吗？
You hear me?
不是这样的。
That isn't true.
根本没有“不”这个词！
"Ain't" isn't even a real word!
该死的婊子！
Goddamn bitch!
真没用。
Useless.
爸爸把妈妈的一切痕迹都烧掉了。
Pa took to burning any trace of Ma.
把你的东西从我家拿走。
Get your shit out of my house.
然后有一天。
And then one day...
他走了。
he was gone.
不像妈妈离开时那么痛苦。
Wasn't like the pain when Ma left.
但是，完全孤独是一种感觉，如此广阔，它回荡。
But being completely alone
was a feeling so vast, it echoed.
还有一个小问题就是生存。
And there was the small matter
of surviving.
我不知道没有燕麦怎么生活。
I didn't know
how to do life without grits.
你好 Kya 小姐。
Well, hello, Miss Kya.
你想要什么吗？
You want something?
跳跃先生。
Mr. Jumpin'...
我听说你们都买贻贝。
I hear tell y'all buy mussels.
我这里有一些。
I got some here.
- 是新鲜的吗?-黎明前挖出来的。
- They fresh?
- Dug them before dawn.
就刚才。
Just now.
你爸爸让你带着这个出去？
Your pa sent you out with these?
这样吧，我给你50美分买一袋
Look, I tell you what,
I'll give you 50 cent for the one bag
另一个加满油。
and a full tank of gas for the other.
你们一周需要多少袋？
How many bags y'all need a week?
我们是在做生意吗？
Are we striking up a business deal?
我每两三天买40磅。
I buy about 40 pound
every two, three days.
提醒你一下，其他人也带来了。
Mind you, others bring them too.
如果你带来了，而我已经有了,
So if you bring them,
and I already got some,
为什么，你只是出去了。
why, you'd just be out.
先到先得，没有别的办法。
It's first come, first served.
Ain't no other way of doing it.
没关系，谢谢。
That's fine. Thank you.
我能..？
Can I, uh...?
哦，是的。
Oh, yeah.
你长得真快啊？
You sure are growing up fast, huh?
不如你下周过来，我给你量尺寸。
Why don't you come by next week,
I'll measure your feet.
我在教堂的捐赠箱里找到了一些鞋子，正在积灰。
I got some shoes in the church
donation bin just collecting dust.
- 谢谢你，女士-不客气。
- Thank you, ma'am.
- Sure.
可怜的孩子。
Poor child.
她妈妈走了，现在她爸爸也走了，我打赌。
Her ma's gone,
and now her pa's gone too, I bet.
什么？
What?
我们应该小心，在民间事务中捣乱。
We ought to be careful,
messing in folk business.
圣经里可没这么说。
It don't say that in the Bible.
“小心点”
"Be careful."
国王会回答他们说,
"And the King shall answer
and say unto them,
我实在告诉你们，因为你们行了这事
verily I say unto thee,
inasmuch as ye hath done it
至少我的弟兄们，你们这样待我。”
unto the least of these,
my brethren, ye have done it unto me."
好吧，梅宝。
All right, Mabel.
别说什么“小心点”
Don't say about "be careful."
我看看。
Let's see.
一，二，三，就这样。
One, two, three. That's all.
是梅布尔小姐送的。
They're from Miss Mabel.
来自 Barkley County 的凯瑟琳・丹妮尔・克拉克,
Catherine Danielle Clark,
of Barkley County, North Carolina,
被指控犯有一级谋杀罪
is charged with the murder
in the first degree
蔡斯 · 劳伦斯 · 安德鲁斯,
of Chase Lawrence Andrews,
以前住在巴克利湾。
formerly of Barkley Cove.
在这种情况下，州政府可以要求判处死刑。
In such cases, the State is allowed
to seek the death penalty.
检方已经宣布将这样做
The prosecution has announced
it will do so
如果被告被判有罪。
if the defendant is found guilty.
有罪，我们都知道她有罪。
Guilty! We all know she's guilty.
她有罪。
She's guilty.
现在开始挑选陪审团成员。
We will now begin jury selection.
前两排的候选陪审员。
Will our prospective jurors
in the first two rows...
还有一个选择，那就是辩诉交易。
There is an option.
It's what's called a plea bargain.
意思是如果你愿意说
And it means
that if you are willing to say
你那晚确实去了塔楼在那里遇到了蔡斯 · 安德鲁斯
that you did go to the tower that night
and met Chase Andrews there
然后你们意见不合发生了一场可怕的事故
and you had a disagreement,
and in a horrible accident
他向后退了几步，穿过栅栏,
he stepped backwards through the grate,
你会被判十年，但六年就能出狱。
you'd get ten years,
but you'd be out in six.
没有。
No.
如果我们输了，我们会输得很惨。
If we lose, we lose big.
不然就是终身监禁。
It's life in prison, or the other.
弥尔顿先生，我不会说任何有罪的话。
Mr. Milton, I won't say anything
that implies guilt.
我不会坐牢的。
I will not go to prison.
请叫我汤姆。
Please call me Tom.
答应我你会考虑一下。
And promise me
that you will think about this.
我必须离开这里。
I have to get out of here.
一种方法。
One way...
或者另一个。
or the other.
10月30日午夜到凌晨2点之间。
Between midnight and 2 a.m.
on October 30th...
被告把蔡斯 · 安德鲁斯引诱到塔里把他推向死亡。
the defendant lured Chase Andrews
to the tower and pushed him to his death.
然后她掩盖了自己的踪迹和指纹。
She then covered up her tracks
and fingerprints.
你会听到她有时间，有动力,
Now, you're gonna hear she had the time,
she had the motivation,
但最重要的是。
but most importantly...
她的性格弱点就是杀了 Chase Andrews。
she has the weakness of character
to murder Chase Andrews.
女士们先生们，州政府会对你们大加指责
Ladies and gentlemen, the State is going
to throw a lot of words at you
凯瑟琳 · 丹妮尔 · 克拉克小姐的事。
about Miss Catherine Danielle Clark.
但我要你看看证据
But I am asking you
to look at the evidence
州政府愿意支持这些说法。
that the State will be offering
to back up those words.
你会发现根本没有。
You'll find that there is none.
此外，你会听到，有一个很好的机会
Furthermore, you are going to hear
that there's a good chance
没有人谋杀蔡斯 · 安德鲁斯被告克拉克小姐,
no one murdered Chase Andrews
and that the defendant, Miss Clark,
发现自己在这里，因为责怪外人更容易
finds herself here because it is easier
to lay blame on an outsider
而不是依靠事实。
than it is to rely on facts.
虽然她出生长大的地方离这个法庭不到五英里,
And although she was born and grew up
not five miles from this courtroom,
克拉克小姐是个局外人。
Miss Clark is an outsider.
哦。
Oh.
嗨。
Hi.
是我，塔特。
It's me. Tate.
苔原天鹅。
Tundra swan.
- 你怎么知道鸟的?-我妈喜欢鸟。
- How do you know birds?
- My ma liked birds.
我看不清你的字条。
I can't read your note.
我只是说我钓鱼的时候见过你几次,
Oh, all I said was I'd seen you
a couple times when I was out fishing,
这让我想到也许你可以用一些种子和火花塞。
and it got me thinking that maybe
you could use some seeds and a spark plug.
我有多余的，我想这样你就不用去镇上了。
I had extra.
Thought it might save you a trip to town.
我不知道，我觉得你会喜欢这些羽毛。
And, uh, I don't know,
I figured you'd like the feathers.
那好吧。
All right, then.
我得走了，所以..。
Well, I better be going, so...
我可以教你识字。
I could teach you to read.
我想你也可以同时学习写作。
I thought you may as well learn
to write at the same time.
哦，是的。
Oh, yeah.
很好，我们从 A 开始。
Good. Okay, so we start with A.
把这个形状画在这里。
Just go ahead
and draw that shape right there.
别告诉我。
Don't tell me.
差不多了。
You're getting there.
- 别帮我-当然，我有一整天的时间。
- Don't help me.
- Sure. I got all day.
“有些人可以活下去
"There are some who can live
没有野生动物，逗号,
without wild things, comma,
而有些人则无能为力。”
and some who cannot."
这就是我说的，Kya！
That's what I'm talking about, Kya. Whoo!
再也不会有你不识字的时候了。
And there will never be a time again
where you can't read, ever.
我不知道语言能承受这么多。
I didn't know words could hold so much.
不是所有的话都那么有说服力。
Not all words hold that much.
我们可以找个时间在我家看书。
We could read at my house sometime.
我们翻遍了整个图书馆。
We went through the whole library.
一周三次，夏天到秋天。
Three times a week, summer into fall.
阅读植物和动物是如何随着时间而变化的
Read how plants
and animals change over time
来适应不断变化的地球。
to adjust to the ever-shifting earth.
鸟儿是如何在黎明时分因为清晨凉爽潮湿的空气而歌唱的呢
How birds sing mostly at dawn
because the cool, moist air of morning
把他们的歌声和意义带到更远的地方。
carries their songs
and their meanings much farther.
一些细胞是如何分裂并分化成肺或心脏的
How some cells divide
and specialize into lungs or hearts
而另一些则作为干细胞保持不定期
while others remain uncommitted
as stem cells
以防以后需要。
in case they're needed later.
在所有的生物学世界里。
Within all the worlds of biology...
我在寻找一个母亲为什么要离开自己的孩子的解释。
I searched for an explanation of why
a mother would leave her offspring.
杰克逊・亨利・克拉克先生
"Mr. Jackson Henry Clark
1933年6月12日与朱丽安 · 玛丽亚 · 雅克小姐结婚
married Miss Julienne Maria Jacques,
June 12, 1933."
也就是说他们是我的父母。
That means these are my parents.
“杰里米 · 安德鲁 · 克拉克大师，一月二日”
"Master Jeremy Andrew Clark, January 2."
那是朱迪。
That's Jodie.
纳比尔 · 墨菲 · 克拉克大师，玛丽 · 海伦 · 克拉克小姐,
"Master Napier Murphy Clark,
Miss Mary Helen Clark,
凯瑟琳 · 丹妮尔 · 克拉克小姐”
Miss Catherine Danielle Clark."
我想念他们。
I miss them.
我..。
I had, um...
我都忘了。
I had forgot how much...
我感觉他们不在这里。
I feel them not here.
但是..。
But...
我感觉他们现在不在这里。
I feel them not here right now.
我是说..。
I mean...
有时候我觉得自己像隐形人。
Sometimes I feel so invisible...
我不知道我是否还在这里。
I wonder if I'm here at all.
你才是。
You are.
- 抱歉我迟到了-来吧，帮我一把。
- Sorry I'm late.
- Come on. Give me a hand.
儿子，你知道我不听空谈。
Son, you know I don't listen to idle talk.
但是流言四起
But there is a regular riptide
of gossip going around
你和那个沼泽女孩有一腿。
you got something going on
with that Marsh Girl.
嘿，你知道你可以告诉我任何事。
Hey, you know you can tell me anything.
- 她是你女朋友?-她是我朋友。
- She your girlfriend?
- She's my friend.
我把她的书带来，因为人们对她很恶劣，她不能去上学。
I bring her books 'cause people are
so nasty to her, she can't go to school.
她没有家人。
She doesn't have any family.
嘿，别这样，没必要这么生气。
Hey. Come on. There's no need to be huffy.
我的工作就是说出所有我们不喜欢谈论的事情,
It's my job to say all the things
that we don't like to talk about,
我不能给你很多其他爸爸能给他们儿子的东西。
and I can't give you a lot of things
those other dads can give their sons.
所以我问你。
So I'm asking you.
小心点。
Just be careful.
你为之努力奋斗的一切你去教堂山的梦想。
Everything you've worked so hard for,
your dreams of going to Chapel Hill...
生活瞬息万变。
Life can change in a second.
你明白吗？
You understand that?
是的。
Yeah.
现在把音乐开大声点，好吗? 来吧。
Now turn up my music, would you? Come on.
是普契尼，如果你想知道的话。
It's Puccini, in case you're wondering.
一个年轻女孩独自生活看起来很不道德，你不觉得吗？
A young girl living on her own
like that looks immoral, don't you think?
不，先生，我不知道，想一想。
No, sir. I don't. Think, that is.
至少不够，问问我老婆就知道了。
At least not enough. Just ask my wife.
有一些很好的教养院可以帮助年轻女性
There are some fine group homes
that would help keep a young woman
摆脱麻烦。
out of trouble.
他们说她经常来这里。
They say she comes in here
from time to time.
我的确时不时会见到她。
I do see her from time to time.
她不是一个人，还有她父亲陪着。
She's not alone.
She's got her father with her.
我从没见过任何人回家。
Well, I've never seen anybody home
all the times I've been by.
她通常什么时候来？
When does she usually come around?
我不知道她什么时候会来。
I never know
just when she'll boat in here.
下次她来的时候让她给我打电话。
Have her call me next time she comes in.
你没理由对我撒谎吧，小子？
You don't have any reason
to lie to me, do you, boy?
完全没有理由，先生。
No reason at all, sir.
- 我们得去别的地方见面-嗨 Kya 很高兴见到你。
- We gotta meet somewhere else.
- Hi, Kya. Good to see you too.
社会福利署又在找我了。
Social Services are looking for me again.
他们会把我关进教养院。
They're gonna pull me in,
put me in some group home.
当你看到别人时，向他们打招呼是有礼貌的。
It's polite to greet people
when you see them.
你知道，团体之家也许不是最糟糕的事。
You know, a group home
might not be the worst thing.
什么? 不，不，你会让别人给你做饭。
What? No, no. You'd have
someone cooking you warm meals.
- 真正的床-我有一张真正的床。
- Real bed.
- I got a real bed.
另外，我绝不会离开沼泽去和一群陌生人住在一起。
'Sides, I'd never leave the marsh
to go live with a bunch of strangers.
是“除此之外”不是“边”
It's "besides," not "'sides."
你不能永远一个人住在沼泽里。
And you can't live alone
in the marsh forever.
看我的。
Watch me.
好吧。
All right.
塔特。
Tate.
我..。
I, um...
谢谢你教我识字
I appreciate you teaching me to read
还有你给我的一切。
and all the things you gave me.
但你为什么要这么做？
But why do you do it?
你没有女朋友什么的吗？
Don't you have a girlfriend or something?
有时候会。
Sometimes I do.
有时候？
Sometimes?
我是说，我有过一次。
I mean, I've had one.
但现在不行。
Uh, but not now...
我不知道，所以..。
I don't, so...
好吧。
Uh, all right.
我，呃..。
I, uh...
那天我看到你在你爸爸的船上。
I saw you on your pa's boat the other day.
你爸爸看起来人很好。
He seems real nice, your dad.
是的，是的，他是。
Yeah. Yeah, he is.
你从来不提你妈妈。
You never talk about your ma.
她人怎么样？
What's she like?
你什么都不用说。
Uh, you don't have to say nothing.
我母亲和妹妹死于阿什维尔的一场车祸。
My mother and little sister died
in a car wreck over in Asheville.
我妹妹的名字叫 Carianne。
My little sister's name was Carianne.
那是，呃..。
It was, uh...
怎么了，塔特？
What, Tate?
你可以对我说任何事。
You can say anything to me.
我想他们是去阿什维尔给我买生日礼物了。
I think they went to Asheville
to buy me my birthday present.
我想要一辆自行车,
There was this bike I wanted,
而西部汽车公司没有。
and Western Auto didn't carry it...
所以我想他们去阿什维尔是为了给我买那辆自行车。
so I think they went into Asheville
to get that bike for me.
哦。
Oh.
我都不记得是什么样的自行车了。
And I don't even remember
what kind of bike it was.
这不是你的错。
It wasn't your fault.
噢！
Oh!
我的天啊！
Oh, my gosh!
我现在是你女朋友了吗？
Am I your girlfriend now?
你想吗？
Do you wanna be?
我了解羽毛。
I know feathers.
我打赌其他女孩不知道羽毛。
Bet the other girls don't know feathers.
那好吧。
All right, then.
- 我从没走过这条路-值得一试。
- I've never been out this way.
- It's worth the trip.
你会明白的。
You'll see.
生日快乐，Kya。
Happy birthday, Kya.
你怎么知道今天是我生日？
How'd you know it was my birthday?
我在你的圣经里读到的。
Oh, I read it in your Bible.
你知道今天是你生日吗？
Did you know it was your birthday?
没有日历。
Don't have a calendar.
不是我的名字。
Oh, um, not my name.
别剪我的名字。
Don't cut my name.
是的，女士。
Yes, ma'am.
- 嗯!-不错吧？
- Mm!
- Pretty good, huh?
那是什么？
What's that?
他们来了。
Here they come.
哦，哇。
Oh, wow.
雪雁。
Snow geese.
Kya.
Kya 看着我。
Kya, look at me.
Kya.
Kya，对不起。
Kya, I'm sorry.
对不起。
I'm sorry.
天啊。
Jeez.
不，塔特，我想。
No, Tate, I want to.
为什么不呢？
Why not?
因为我..。
Because I...
我太在乎你了。
I care about you too much.
听着，Kya，我最想要的就是你，但是我不会那么容易受伤。
Look, Kya. I want you more than anything,
but I can't be damaged as easily.
对你来说更危险，明白吗？
It's more dangerous for you.
You understand?
秋天让位于冬天。
Fall gave way to winter.
从冬天到春天。
Winter to spring.
自然界唯一不变的就是变化。
The only constant in nature is change.
爸爸，我被录取了！
Dad, I got in!
你怎么不说话？
Why are you quiet?
你知道我很快就要走了。
You know I'm going away soon.
去上大学。
To college.
你们谈过了。
You talked about it.
什么时候？
When?
不是马上。
Not right away.
很快。
Soon.
我在生物实验室找了份工作。
I got a job at the biology lab.
下周开始，所以..。
Starts next week, so...
待在这儿。
Stay here.
然后呢？
And do what?
不，听着，我只是说这里没有我的工作。
No, look. I just mean
there's no work for me here.
我该怎么办? 我不想像我爸爸一样做捕虾人。
What am I gonna do?
I don't want to be a shrimper like my dad.
我要拿到学位，成为一个伟大的人，Kya。
I'm going to get a degree
and be something, Kya.
- 你也可以-你想让我成为什么？
- So could you.
- What do you want me to be?
- 我不是这个意思-你再也不会回来了。
- That's not what I meant.
- You're never gonna come back.
是的，我会的，我不会离开你的，Kya，我保证。
Yes, I will. I won't leave you, Kya.
I promise.
我会回到你身边的。
I'm gonna come back to you.
姬雅! 姬雅，住手! Ky. ..。
Kya! Kya, stop! Ky...
你不能逃避每一针！
You can't run away from every whip stitch!
- 再一晚上-再一晚上。
- One more night.
这是什么？
What's this?
这是出版商的名单。
It's a list of publishers.
你所有的图纸和笔记。
For all your drawings and notes.
外面没有像他们一样的人，Kya。
There's nothing like them out there, Kya.
足够买一本书了。
There's enough for a book.
很多书。
Lots of books.
而且，你知道，你不必离开家。
And, you know,
you wouldn't have to leave home.
你可以把样品寄给出版商。
You could just mail your samples
into a publisher.
赚点钱。
You know, bring some money in.
你知道，可能不是很多..。
You know, probably not a huge amount...
但也许你下半辈子就不用挖贻贝了。
but maybe you wouldn't have
to dig mussels the rest of your life.
试试吧，Kya。
Just give it a try, Kya.
拜托，有什么大不了的？
Come on. What can it hurt?
你会忘了我的。
You're gonna forget about me.
当你忙于大学的事情时,
When you get busy
with all that college stuff,
那些漂亮女孩。
all those pretty girls.
我永远不会忘记你，Kya。
I could never forget you, Kya.
永远不会。
Ever.
我保证一个月后就回家，国庆节那天，好吗？
I'll be home in a month. I promise.
For the Fourth of July. Okay?
我很快就会回来的。
I'll be back before you know it.
我们会在你的沙滩上见面，一起看烟火。
We'll meet on your beach
and watch fireworks together.
给那些出版商写信，好吗？
Just write those publishers, all right?
再见，Kya。
Goodbye, Kya.
再见，塔特。
Goodbye, Tate.
美国东岸的海鸟。
Seabirds of the Eastern Seaboard.
由你主演，大红。
Starring you, Big Red.
没有。
No.
不，塔特。
No, Tate.
不，不。
No, no.
没有。
No.
不，不，不。
No, no, no.
泰特，生活和爱情是一回事。
Tate and life
and love had been the same thing.
他们都走了。
They were all gone.
然后..。
And then...
每当我跌跌撞撞的时候，沼泽就会抓住我。
Whenever I stumbled, the marsh caught me.
在某个无人知晓的时刻,
At some unclaimed moment,
最后，心痛慢慢消失了,
at last, the heart pain seeped away,
就像水变成了沙子。
like water into sand.
还在，但很深。
Still there, but deep.
尸体周围和消防塔上都没有脚印。
There were no footprints
around the body or on the fire tower.
也没有新的指纹。
And no fresh fingerprints either.
甚至在壁炉上也没有，有人必须打开它。
Not even on the grate,
which somebody had to open.
所有这些都表明有人销毁了证据。
All this indicated
that someone had destroyed evidence.
没有问题了。
No more questions.
该你问了。
Your witness.
警长，我把潮汐表递给你
Sheriff,
I'm handing you the tide table
10月29日晚上和10月30日早上。
for the night of October 29
and the morning of October 30.
这里显示的低潮时间是在午夜左右。
Now, this shows here
that low tide was around midnight.
所以当 Chase Andrews 到达塔楼的时候
So at the time
Chase Andrews arrived at the tower
然后走到台阶上，他会在湿泥地上留下脚印。
and walked to the steps,
he would have made tracks in the wet mud.
然后随着地下水位上升，这些痕迹就会消失。
And then as the groundwater rose,
those tracks would have been wiped out.
- 你同意这是可能的吗?-嗯..。
- Do you agree that this is possible?
- Well...
然后你就会同意如果他有朋友的话,
And then you'd agree
that if he had any friends with him,
他们的脚印也会被冲走。
their footprints would be
washed away as well.
在这种情况下,
Under these circumstances,
没有足迹本身并不意味着犯罪。
the absence of footprints in
and of itself does not suggest a crime.
对吗？
Correct?
警长？
Sheriff?
没有脚印本身并不能证明这是一起犯罪。
The absence of footprints does not,
by itself, prove there was a crime.
你还作证说没有指纹
You also testified
that there were no fingerprints
在消防塔的任何地方都能找到，包括在敞开的壁炉上。
found anywhere in the fire tower,
including on the open grate.
所以这让你得出结论，一定是有人打开了栅栏
So this led you to conclude
that someone must have opened the grate
然后擦掉他们的指纹。
and wiped away
their fingerprints afterwards.
没错。
Correct.
事实上，这些栅栏是不是一直开着
Now, in fact, isn't it true
that these grates were left open
经常被认为是危险的
so often and considered so dangerous
你的办公室提交了一份书面申请
that your office submitted
a written request
美国林务局
to the U.S. Forest Service
去年七月十八日的情况怎么补救？
to remedy the situation
on July 18 of last year?
这是那个请求的副本。
This is a copy of that request.
这是谁写的，警长？
Who wrote this, sheriff?
我自己做的。
I did it myself.
你能向法庭宣读这份文件的最后一句话吗
Would you read to the court
the last sentence of this document
你发给林务局的？
that you sent to the Forest Service?
最后一句。
Just the last sentence.
”我必须重申，这些栅栏非常危险,
"I must repeat,
these grates are very dangerous,
如果不采取行动。
and if action is not taken...
如果不采取行动，就会造成严重的伤亡。”
If action is not taken,
a serious injury or death will occur."
谢谢你，警长。
Thank you, sheriff.
有人在我家附近拍照。
Somebody's been taking pictures
round my house.
你觉得他们想要什么？
What do you think they want?
开发商。
Developers.
过去几周他们一直在沼泽地上上下下,
They've been all up and down
the marsh last few weeks,
想要排干“黑暗沼泽”建酒店。
wanting to drain the "murky swamp."
Build hotels.
是的，我去年见过他们。
Yeah, I saw them last year.
砍伐橡树，挖掘沟渠。
Cutting oak and digging channels
down the way.
他们想要我的房子？
They want my house?
也许不是房子,
Maybe not the house,
但我打赌他们会给你一大笔钱买那块地。
but I bet they offer you
a heap of money for that land.
跳！
Jumpin'!
把钱给 Kya 没什么不好。
There ain't nothing wrong
with some money going to Kya.
那块地是你的，对吧? 那房子是你的？
You do own that land, don't you?
You own that house?
爸爸说的。
Pa said so.
你需要一些证据。
Well, you're gonna need some proof.
契约，头衔。
A deed, title.
嘿。
Hey.
抱歉吓到你了，我帮你拿吧？
Sorry to startle you.
Can I carry that for ya?
- 我来吧-拜托，让我来吧。
- I got it.
- Please. Let me get it.
我是蔡斯 · 安德鲁斯。
Oh, I'm Chase Andrews.
你叫 Kya 对吧？
Your name's Kya, right?
是啊，是个好名字，我喜欢，与众不同但很好听。
Yeah. Yeah. It's a nice name.
I like it. It's different but nice.
这是你的。
This is yours right here.
好了。
There we go.
这周日想去我的船上野餐吗？
You wanna go for a picnic
in my boat this Sunday?
好吧。
Okay.
我中午去波因特海滩接你，可以吗？
I'll pick you up at noon
from Point Beach. Does that work?
好吧，回头见 Kya。
All right. Well, I'll see ya, Kya.
我们到了。
Well, here we are.
纳比尔 · 克拉克先生，看起来像是1897年买的。
Mr. Napier Clark, looks like,
bought it in 1897.
是的，那是我爷爷。
Yeah, uh, that's my grandpa.
是的，女士。
Yes, ma'am.
它从来没有被卖掉过，所以，是的，先生，我想它是属于你的。
It's never been sold, so, yes sirree,
I reckon it belongs to you.
克拉克小姐，看来你要想保住它，就得补交一些税款。
Looks like you gotta pay some back taxes
if you wanna keep it, Miss Clark.
事实上，女士，根据法律规定,
In fact, ma'am, the way the law reads, uh,
不管是谁，只要付了税就能拥有这片土地,
whoever comes along and pays
those back taxes owns the land,
即使他们没有契约。
even if they don't got no deed.
多少钱？
Well, how much?
看起来像是..。
Looks like about...
一共八百块。
Eight hundred dollars total.
五年了。
Five years.
距离塔特向我展示这条道路已经过去五年了。
It had been five years
since Tate showed me this path.
尊敬的先生或女士:
Dear Sir or Madam,
我寄给你以下关于卡罗莱纳州沼泽地贝壳的页面
I am sending you the following pages
on the shells of the Carolina marsh
供您参考。
for your consideration.
五年，我的心再次打开它的壳。
Five years for my heart
to open its shell again.
在音乐天才面前晒太阳的感觉怎么样？
How's it feel to bask
in the presence of musical genius?
嘿，看。
Hey, look.
哦，哦! 那是个华丽的扇贝。
Oh. Oh! That's an ornate scallop.
佩顿华纳塔斯。
Pecten ornatus.
好吧。
All right.
- 这里很少见-真的吗？
- Well, it's unusual to find one here.
- Really?
是的，这种特殊的物种通常生活在这里以南的地区
Yeah. This particular species usually
inhabits regions south of here
因为这些水对它们来说太凉了。
'cause these waters are too cool for them.
什么？
What?
不，只是沼泽女孩知道贝壳的拉丁名字
Oh, no, it's just, the Marsh Girl knows
the Latin name for shells
看在上帝的份上，他们住在哪里，为什么。
and where they inhabit and why,
for Christ sakes.
给你，你留着吧。
Here. You keep it.
谢谢你。
Thank you.
你很特别，不是吗？
You're something else, ain't ya?
我知道你觉得我是垃圾，但我比野餐更有价值。
I know you think I'm trash,
but I'm worth more than a picnic.
哦，不，Kya，别这样。
Oh, no, Kya. Come on.
对不起，不，嘿，别这样，我从没觉得你是垃圾。
I'm sorry. No. Hey, come on.
I've never thought you were trash.
求你了，对不起。
Please. I'm sorry.
如果你想走，我能理解，但你不能从这里走。
I understand if you wanna go,
but you can't walk from here.
太远了。
It's too far.
我能补偿你吗？
Can I make it up to you?
求你了，我能补偿你吗？
Please, can I make it up to you?
真不敢相信你从来没上过消防塔。
I can't believe
you never been up the fire tower.
当我的家人都在做我的生意的时候，你就过来，知道吗？
Come here when my family's
all in my business. You know?
这是从空中俯瞰整个沼泽地的好方法。
It's a great way to see
the whole marsh from above.
给你。
Here.
这是什么？
What is it?
你可以告诉我，我不会嘲笑你的。
You can tell me. I won't laugh at you.
就像一辈子都有一个朋友，但你从没见过他们的真面目。
It's like having a friend your whole life,
but you never saw their full face.
现在我明白了。
Now I see it.
你的房子在那边，是吗？
Your house is over there, ain't it?
带我去。
Take me there.
哦，呃..。
Oh, um...
- 很远-嘿，我喜欢远。
- It's far.
- Hey, I like far.
我不在乎是什么感觉，如果你担心的是这个的话。
I don't care what it's like,
if that's what you're worried about.
就是这里吗？
Is this it right here?
你一个人在这里住了多久？
How long you lived out here by yourself?
大概十年了吧。
Uh, about ten years, I think.
干净利落。
Neat.
住在这里，没有父母告诉你该做什么？
Living out here with no parents
telling you what to do?
里面真的没什么好看的。
There's really nothing to see inside.
- 哇，门廊上有什么?-什么？
- Wow, what you got on the porch?
- What?
没什么。
Oh, um, nothing.
这些都是什么？
What is all this?
没什么。
Nothing.
怎么，你在写书吗？
What, you writing a book or something?
算是吧。
Sort of.
这些看起来就像是从百科全书里学来的。
These look straight out
of an encyclopedia.
你是真材实料，不是吗？
You're the real deal, ain't ya?
斯旺尼。
Ah, swanee.
你有水泵。
You got a water pump.
我还没准备好迎接客人。
I wasn't ready for guests.
别担心。
Hey, don't worry.
嘿，我认识的人里没人能一个人住在这种地方。
Hey, there's nobody I know
who could live out here alone like this.
我是说，大多数男人都会害怕。
I mean, most guys would be too scared.
你找我干什么？
What do you want with me?
好吧，听着，我真的很抱歉我那样说。
Okay. Look, I'm real sorry
I came on like that.
我想更了解你，好吗？
I wanna get to know you better. All right?
我觉得你很漂亮。
I think you're gorgeous.
真的，我觉得你自由自在，聪明绝顶。
I do. I think you're free as a dang gale
and smart as a whip.
但除非你要我做什么，否则我什么都不会做。
But I won't do anything
unless you want me to.
怎么样？
How's that?
没关系。
That's fine.
好吧。
All right.
我不知道自己对 Chase 是什么感觉。
I didn't know
exactly how I felt about Chase.
但我不再孤单。
But I was no longer lonely.
这就够了。
That seemed enough.
这是为你的书准备的吗？
Is that for your book?
是的。
Yeah.
不管怎样，谁知道会不会有人看到。
Anyway, who knows if anyone will read it.
我会的。
I will.
沼泽地是我们的秘密。
The marsh was our secret.
跟我说说你的朋友。
Tell me about your friends.
我没什么朋友。
Oh, I don't really have any friends.
你和他们在一起的时候似乎总是很开心。
You always seem to be having
a good time when you're with them.
你在监视我吗？
You spying on me?
有趣的是，我爸爸曾经告诉我,
It's funny. My dad told me once,
他喝了点酒，还和我妈吵了一架。
he'd had something to drink
and a fight with my mom.
他告诉我，如果我的朋友真的了解我，他们就不会是我的朋友。
He told me if my friends really knew me,
they wouldn't be my friends.
我不知道是否有人真正了解我，这就是我想说的。
I don't know if anyone really knows me,
is what I'm saying, I guess.
我想知道是什么让天空变蓝。
I wonder what makes the sky blue.
来自阳光的蓝色和紫色波长。
Blue and violet wavelengths from sunlight.
它们会弹开大气中的气体粒子然后散开。
They, uh, bounce off the gas particles
in the atmosphere and scatter.
我能不能..。
Is it okay if I...
现在吻你？
kiss you now?
让我们看看发现的红色羊毛纤维
Let's turn
to the red wool fibers found
在 Chase Andrews 的牛仔夹克上
on Chase Andrews' denim jacket
他死的那晚。
the night he died.
你把这些样本和这顶红色滑雪帽比对了吗？
Did you compare those samples
to this red ski cap?
证据三。
Exhibit C.
是的，帽子和夹克上的纤维完全吻合。
Yes. The fibers from the cap
and the jacket matched exactly.
帽子是在哪找到的？
And where was that cap found?
在克拉克小姐的住处找到的。
It was found
in Miss Clark's residence.
关于这些红色纤维，医生,
Now, about these red fibers,
is there any way, doctor,
来确定纤维在夹克上多久了？
to determine how long
the fibers had been on the jacket?
不，我们知道他们从哪来，不知道什么时候。
No. We can tell
where they came from, not when.
如果有人经常戴这顶帽子,
And if someone wore this hat often,
有没有可能纤维会出现在她们的头发和衣服上？
is it possible the fibers would be
in their hair and on their clothes?
是的，我想他们可以。
Yes. I would suppose they could.
那么你是否同意这些年来
So would you agree
that at any time during the years
被告 Clark 小姐认识 Chase Andrews,
that the defendant, Miss Clark,
knew Chase Andrews,
帽子的纤维可能被转移到 Chase 的夹克上？
the fibers of the hat could have been
transferred onto Chase's jacket?
在我看来，是的。
From what I've seen, yes.
- 他们见面的任何时候-是的。
- At any time they met.
- Yes.
“亲爱的克拉克小姐，我们被你的手稿迷住了”
"Dear Miss Clark,
we were fascinated by your manuscript."
如果像你说的，你的材料已经完成了,
If, as you say,
your materials are already complete,
“我们希望能在创纪录的时间内编辑出版”
"we hope to edit
and publish in record time."
你面前的是西部汽车公司的新经理。
Hey. You're looking
at the new manager of Western Auto.
切斯，这..。
Oh, Chase, that's...
- 真是好消息-来吧，我们庆祝一下。
- That's great news.
- Come on. Let's celebrate.
他们会付你钱买画吗？
So they're gonna, uh,
pay you for those drawings?
是的。
Yeah.
哦！
Ooh!
别太自以为是了。
Just don't get too full of yourself,
I guess.
我不会。
I wouldn't.
我知道大家都让你失望了。
I know people have disappointed you.
我很抱歉。
And I'm sorry for that.
被自己的家人抛弃，我是说..。
Getting left by your own family. I mean...
天啊，我的家人真讨厌，但我受不了了。
God, my family's a pain in the ass,
but I don't think I could take that.
但我想让你知道，我会照顾你的。
But I want you to know
that I'm gonna take care of you.
现在我升职了,
Now I've been promoted,
等我们结婚了，我可以给你买栋漂亮的房子。
I can get you a nice house
when we're married.
- “结婚了”?-是的。
- "Married"?
- Yeah.
在海滩上的一个漂亮的两层楼，有一个环绕式的阳台。
A nice two-story on the beach
with a wraparound veranda.
是的。
Yeah.
你父母呢？
What about your parents?
你告诉他们我的事了吗？
Have you told them about me?
你要了解我父母的一些情况
What you gotta understand about my folks
如果我说你是我的选择，那就是了。
is that if I say you're my choice,
that'd be that.
当他们了解你的时候，他们会爱上你的。
They'll fall in love with you
when they get to know ya.
过来。
Come here.
对了我过几天要开车去阿什维尔
Oh, by the way, I have to drive over
to Asheville in a few days
给我爸的店买东西。
to buy goods for my dad's store.
我想你可以一起来。
I was thinking you could come.
- 为你的书庆祝一下-哦..。
- Celebrate your book and all.
- Oh...
- 会有很多人-没关系。
- There'd be lots of people.
- It doesn't matter.
你会和我在一起，我什么都知道。
You'd be with me. I know everything.
见鬼，如果你不想的话，你可以不和任何人说话。
Hell, you don't have to talk to one soul
if you don't want to.
拜托，如果我们要结婚，你得出去走走。
Come on. If we're gonna get married,
you need to get out in the world a bit.
展开你的长翅膀。
Spread those long wings of yours.
来吧，会很好玩的。
Come on. It'll be fun.
这是两天的工作，所以我们要留下来过夜。
It's a two-day job,
so we'll stay the night.
抬起我的头
...hold my head up high
不可思议吧？
Incredible, huh?
让我内心感到甜蜜
Makes me feel sweet inside
嘿，这是个冒险，来吧。
Hey. It's an adventure. Come on.
你做得越多，感觉就越好。
It'll feel better for you later,
the more you do it.
哦。
Oh.
嘿，我永远不想失去你。
Hey, I never wanna lose you.
- 是吗?-是的。
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
我想了很多。
I think about it a lot.
晚上偷偷溜出来见你。
Sneaking out at night to come see you.
我的沼泽女孩。
My Marsh Girl.
没人知道
Nobody knows
没人看得见
Nobody sees
除了我没人知道
Nobody knows but me
你不需要向任何人证明自己，明白吗？
Hey, you don't have to prove yourself
to anyone. You understand?
你有我，我爱你。
You have me, and I love you.
我给你做了点东西。
I made you something.
哦。
Oh.
只有一个弹壳,
It was a single shell,
挂在一块生皮上，打了个紧结，不见了。
hung on a piece of rawhide,
tied in a tight knot, and it was missing.
先说清楚，你的意思是贝壳项链
So to be clear, what you're
saying is that the shell necklace
奇斯每天穿的衣服都不见了
that Chase wore every day
was missing from these items
在他被发现的那天，执法部门从他的尸体上发现了他的尸体。
that law enforcement recovered
from his body the day that he was found.
是这样吗？
Is that correct?
- 我觉得这很重要-是的。
- I think it's important.
- Yes.
那天晚上他和我们一起吃饭的时候戴着那条项链。
He had that necklace on
when he had dinner with us that night.
从他身体里消失了。
And it was gone from his body.
我想说的是，他从没摘下来过。
And what I'm saying is
he never took it off.
杀他的人拿走了。
Whoever killed him took it.
反对，法官大人，这是推测。
Objection, Your Honor. It's speculation.
反对有效。
Sustained.
陪审团的女士们先生们,
Ladies and gentlemen of the jury,
请忽略安德鲁斯太太最后说的话。
you will disregard
that last remark by Mrs. Andrews.
安德鲁斯夫人，蔡斯从哪里得到这条项链的？
Mrs. Andrews,
where did Chase get this necklace?
是那个沼泽女孩克拉克小姐寄来的。
It's from that Marsh Girl.
Miss Clark.
我甚至不知道她的名字，也不知道她有没有名字。
I didn't even know her name
or if she even had one.
我不明白为什么 Chase..。
I can't see why Chase...
但我想说的是,
But what I'm saying is,
她是唯一一个有兴趣接手的人。
she's the only one who'd have
any interest in taking the thing.
安德鲁斯太太。
Mrs. Andrews...
Chase 和 Clark 小姐有没有恋爱关系？
were Chase and Miss Clark
romantically involved?
可以这么说，我看见他晚上溜出去。
You could say.
I saw him sneaking out at night.
当我终于问他要去哪里时，他告诉了我真相。
When I finally asked him
where he was going, he told me the truth.
我想: 人们会怎么说？
I thought: What would people say?
我真是个傻女人，竟然担心这个。
I was a silly woman
to be worried about that next to...
但他告诉我他和她分手了。
But he told me he broke it off with her.
她知道她不能再拥有他了，所以她杀了他
She knew she couldn't have him anymore,
so she killed him
- 拿回了她丑陋的项链-反对，法官大人。
- and took back her ugly necklace!
- Objection, Your Honor.
反对有效。
Sustained.
没有问题了，法官大人。
No further questions,
Your Honor.
安德鲁斯夫人，请节哀顺变。
Um, Mrs. Andrews, you have
my deepest sympathy for your loss.
恕我直言,
With all due respect,
你知道克拉克小姐的房子已经被彻底搜查过了吧。
you are aware that Miss Clark's house
was thoroughly searched.
警察没有在那里找到项链。
And that the police did not find
the necklace there.
- 有吗?-没有。
- Did they?
- No.
嘿。
Hey.
- 我来吧-嘿。
- I got it.
- Hey.
- 差点打到你-差点把我打晕。
- Almost got you.
- Almost knocked me out.
只是想炫耀一下。
Just trying to show off.
那个沼泽女孩在床上是什么样的? 她是动物吗？
What's that Marsh Girl like
in bed, man? Is she an animal?
像山猫一样狂野，值得每一分油钱。
Wild as a bobcat and worth
every bit of the gas money.
告诉我她的眼睛在发光。
Tell me her eyes glow.
- 只对我而言，而且只在我做的时候-嘿，别这么说她。
- Only for me and only when I make them.
- Hey, don't talk about her like that.
- 那是什么?-我说了别这么说她。
- What's that?
- I said don't talk about her like that.
哦，那个大学生。
Oh, the college boy.
- 他教沼泽女孩 ABC-哦。
- He taught the Marsh Girl her ABCs.
- Oh.
- 嗯-你在浪费她的时间。
- Mmm.
- You're a waste of her time.
来吧，大学生，你想怎么样？
Go ahead, college boy. What you gonna do?
- 来吧，你很坚强，对吧?-来吧，我们做点什么。
- Come on, you're tough, right?
- Come on, let's do something.
- 你想打我吗?-嘿，你们都冷静点。
- You wanna hit me?
- Hey, y'all settle down now.
够了。
That's enough.
在有人受伤之前冷静下来。
Settle down before someone get hurt.
有比这更好的办法。
There's better ways than this.
嘿 Kya。
Hey, Kya.
嘿，怎么回事？
Hey, what the hell?
等等! Kya 等等! 求你了。
Wait! Kya, wait! Please.
听着，我只是想谈谈。
Look, I just wanna talk.
滚出我的泻湖，你这个卑鄙小人！
Get out of my lagoon, you dirty creep!
Kya 求你了! 我只是想和你谈谈！
Kya, please! I just need to talk to you!
我不管你想要什么！
I don't care what you want!
我再也不想见到你，再也不想。
I never wanna see you again. Ever.
Kya 我得跟你谈谈 Chase 好吗？
Kya, I need to talk to you
about Chase, okay?
- 关于 Chase?-他配不上你。
- About Chase?
- He's not good enough for you.
是你离开了我。
You're the one who left me.
你答应的时候他没有回来，他再也没有回来。
Who didn't come back when you promised.
Who never came back.
你甚至没有写信解释，甚至没有说你是生是死。
You didn't even write to explain
or even to say if you were alive or dead.
你就这么消失了。
You just disappeared.
我知道，我很抱歉 Kya 你不知道。
I know. And I'm so sorry, Kya,
you have no idea.
你不够男人，不敢面对我。
You weren't man enough to face me.
你说得对，Kya。
You're right, Kya.
你说的都是真的。
Everything you say is true.
像那样离开你是我做过的最糟糕的事,
Leaving you like that was
the worst thing I've ever done,
我这辈子做过的最糟糕的事。
the worst thing I'll ever do in my life.
我知道我会伤你很深，我无法面对你，就像你说的。
I knew how badly I'd hurt you,
and I couldn't face you, like you said.
我还以为你不能离开沼泽，去其他世界生活呢。
I thought you wouldn't be able to leave
the marsh and live in any other world.
我以为我必须在你和其他事情之间做出选择。
You know, I thought I had to choose
between you and everything else.
但事实是，Kya，其他我认为重要的事情,
But the truth is, Kya,
everything else that I thought mattered,
奖学金，助学金，工作，没有你，一切都毫无意义。
the scholarships, the grants, the jobs,
it means nothing without you.
我大错特错了。
I was so wrong.
这么多年来我一直很抱歉。
I've been sorry for years.
我会后悔一辈子的。
And I'll be sorry for the rest of my life.
你看起来..。
You look...
我给你带了点东西。
I brought you something.
我在镇子附近的新实验室工作。
You know, I'm working
at the new lab near town.
你会喜欢的，Kya。
You'd love it, Kya.
我要在显微镜下研究这一切。
I get to study all this
under a microscope.
所以我来了。
So I'm here now.
我永远回来了。
I'm back for good.
Kya 我愿意做任何事..。
Kya, I would do anything to...
我会做很多不同的事情。
I would've done
so many things differently.
你又想怎么样，塔特？
What do you want now, Tate?
你能原谅我吗 Kya？
Is there any way
that you could possibly forgive me, Kya?
求你了？
Please?
我不知道该怎么做。
I don't know how.
Kya，我相信如果你知道其他人，你会告诉我的
Kya, I trust you would tell me
if you knew of anyone else
他有理由伤害 Chase Andrews。
who had reason to harm Chase Andrews.
那好吧。
Well, all right, then.
休息一下吧。
Try and get some rest.
哦，嗨。
Oh. Hi.
嘿，你来城里干什么？
Hey. What you doing in town?
我从出版商那里得到了一些好消息，所以我想我们可以庆祝一下。
I had some good news from the publisher,
so I thought we could celebrate.
- 本来要...-他来了。
- Was gonna make...
- There he is.
Kya，你认识 Brian，Tina，Pearl。
Kya, you know Brian, Tina, Pearl.
- 你们认识 Kya-当然认识，沼泽女孩。
- You guys know Kya.
- Sure, yeah, the Marsh Girl.
很高兴见到你，Kya。
Pleased to meet you, Kya.
我是蔡斯的未婚妻。
I'm Chase's fiancee.
好吧，回头见 Kya。
All right. Well, I'll see you around, Kya.
Kya！
Kya!
嘿 Kya 听我解释。
Hey, Kya. I can explain.
你在里面吗？
Are you in there?
嘿，我只是想谈谈。
Hey, I just wanna talk.
Kya！
Kya!
我知道你在这里，该死的！
I know you're here, damn it!
Kya！
Kya!
我必须独自生活。
I had to do life alone.
但我知道。
But I knew that.
我早就知道了。
I'd known for a long time.
人们不会留下来。
People don't stay.
”亲爱的克拉克小姐,
"Dear Miss Clark,
随函附上你那本漂亮的书的最后一本,
enclosed is the final copy
of your beautiful book,
连同最初的运输支票,
along with the initial check for delivery,
肯定还有版税。
with royalties to follow, I'm sure.
我下个月要去格林维尔参加一个会议
I'm attending a conference
in Greenville next month
希望你们能加入我们，庆祝这一伟大的成就”
and would love for you to join us
and celebrate this great accomplishment."
凯瑟琳 · 丹妮尔 · 克拉克的全权契约
"A full deed for Catherine Danielle Clark
310英亩的泻湖，沼泽，橡树林和海滩。
for 310 acres of lagoons,
marsh, oak forests and beach.
荒地分类: 阴暗的沼泽
Wasteland category: murky swamp."
朱迪？
Jodie?
我在阿什维尔，在一家书店里看到了你的书:
There I am in Asheville,
and I see your book in a shop:
凯瑟琳 · 丹妮尔 · 克拉克。
Catherine Danielle Clark.
我的心都碎了，一下子高兴得跳了起来。
And my heart just broke
and leapt for joy all at once.
我知道我必须找到你。
I knew I had to find you.
我只是没想到你还在这里。
I just didn't think you'd still be here.
其他人呢？
What about the others?
我对墨菲，曼迪和米西一无所知。
I don't know a thing
about Murph, Mandy or Missy.
就算在街上碰到我也认不出来。
I wouldn't know them
if I passed them in the street.
还有..。
And, um...
那妈妈呢？
what about Ma?
妈妈去世了，Kya。
Ma passed, Kya.
妈妈有个妹妹，叫罗斯玛丽。
Ma had a sister, Rosemary.
她在军队里找到我，告诉我发生了什么。
She found me in the Army
and told me what happened.
穿着鳄鱼皮鞋出现在罗斯玛丽家门口。
Showed up at Rosemary's door
in her alligator shoes.
罗斯玛丽说她几个月都不说话。
Rosemary said she didn't talk for months.
大约一年后，她想起她有孩子。
And then about a year later,
she remembered she had children.
罗斯玛丽帮她给爸爸写了一封信，问她能不能来接我们。
Rosemary helped her write a letter to Pa,
asking if she could come get us.
他告诉她如果她再联系我们,
And he told her
if she ever so much as contacted us again,
他会把我们打得面目全非。
he'd beat us unrecognizable.
是啊，听起来像爸爸。
Yeah, sounds like Pa.
她攒钱请律师什么的,
She saved up for lawyers and everything,
但后来她病了。
but then she got sick.
白血病。
Leukemia.
她试过了，但是..。
She tried, but...
她根本没有机会。
She never had a chance.
我一直在等..。
I've been waiting...
这么多年来，她走在这条小路上。
all these years
for her to walk down the lane.
你这辈子都没有家人,
You didn't have a family your whole life,
我也没办法把它还给你。
and there's nothing I can do
to give you that back.
但我想尽可能多地来看你。
But I'd like to come see you
as much as I can get up here.
好啊，我很乐意。
Yeah, I'd like that.
梅宝会为你骄傲的。
Mabel's gonna be so proud.
还有一件事。
Just one more thing.
我保证他会明白的。
I'll be sure he gets it.
谢谢你，跳跃。
Thank you, Jumpin'.
你们好吗？
How y'all doing?
请给我一包最好的，先生。
One pack of your finest, please, sir.
给我一些火柴。
And give me some matches.
- 没问题-没问题
- Sure thing.
- "Sure thing."
Kya Clark.
Catherine Danielle Clark 小姐。
Miss Catherine Danielle Clark.
你写了本该死的书，过来。
You wrote a damn book. Come here.
等等，我想跟你谈谈。
Wait, wait, wait. I wanna talk to you.
别这样，拜托。
Don't act like that. Come on.
别烦我。
Leave me alone.
该死，沼泽女孩觉得你配不上她。
Damn, the Marsh Girl thinks
she's too good for you now.
闭嘴！
Shut up!
给你，先生，免费的。
Here you go, sir. It's on the house.
就知道能在这儿找到你。
Thought I might find you here.
我告诉过你离我远点。
I told you to leave me alone.
不，我知道，但我只是... 听着，我想说对不起。
No, I know, but I just...
Listen, I wanted to say I'm sorry.
真的，我对事情的结果感到很抱歉。
Really. I feel bad about
how things turned out.
“结果如何”？
"How things turned out"?
什么，你是说结果
What, you mean how it turned out
我们在一起的时候你就订婚了？
you were engaged
the whole time we were together?
结果你骗了所有人？
How it turned out
that you lie to everybody?
Kya 我必须做我不想做的事，你知道的。
Kya, I have to do things
I don't wanna do. You know that.
不，我必须嫁给像 Pearl 这样的人，我必须这么做。
No, I have to get married
to someone like Pearl. I had to.
但你才是我真正想要的。
But you're the one I really want.
你知道其他男人会试图改变你吗？
You know any other man
would have tried to change you?
治好你？
To fix you?
我从来没有。
I never did.
不，不，求你了，等等，我需要你，我真的需要你。
No, no. Please, please, wait.
I need you. I really need you.
别把我一个人留在那里。
Don't leave me all alone in that place.
其他人都不认识我。
You know, nobody else knows me.
我为你感到难过。
You know, I feel sorry for you.
但我不想跟这些扯上任何关系。
But I want nothing to do with any of that.
比以前更狂野。
Wilder than ever.
我知道你也想要这个。
I know you want this too.
- 住手!-我知道你也想这样。
- Stop!
- I know you want this too.
你是我的，Kya，你属于我，这次我不会让你走的。
You're mine, Kya. You belong to me.
I'm not letting you go this time.
放开我，你这个混蛋！
Leave me alone, you bastard!
你再来烦我，我就杀了你！
You bother me again and I'll kill you!
她喊得很大声，先生。
She shouted it real loud, sir.
我听到一阵骚动，我走近了一些,
I heard a commotion, and I come closer,
看看有没有人有麻烦，然后她就出现了。
see if anybody was in trouble,
and there she was.
你认识这个女人吗？
And do you recognize the woman?
她今天在法庭上吗？
Is she in the courtroom today?
是的，那边那个，被告。
Yes, that one there. The defendant.
就是那个叫沼泽女孩的人。
The one folks call Marsh Girl.
我终于明白妈妈为什么要离开了。
I finally understood why
Ma had to leave.
我从爸爸那里学到了一件事,
One thing I learned from Pa,
这些人必须打最后一拳。
these men have to have the last punch.
与世隔绝是一回事。
Being isolated was one thing.
生活在恐惧中，完全是另一回事。
Living in fear, quite another.
我永远不会那样生活。
I will never live like that.
不知道下一个拳头何时会落下的生活。
A life wondering
when the next fist will fall.
塔特，你不能来这里。
Tate, you can't be here.
我只是想来看看你。
I just wanted to check on you.
- 他说他很久没见过你了，自从...-现在不行。
- Jumpin' said he hadn't seen you since...
- Not now.
Kya，你的脸怎么了？
Kya, what happened to your face?
是 Chase 吗? 告诉我 Kya 是他干的吗？
Was it Chase?
Tell me, Kya. Did he do this?
我要你别插手。
I need you to stay out of it.
那个狗娘养的。
That son of a bitch.
- 那个狗娘养的-塔特，我需要你离开。
- That son of a bitch.
- Tate, I need you to go.
Kya.
我本打算下周去格林维尔。
You know, I was gonna go
to Greenville next week.
终于见到我的出版商了。
Finally meet my publishers.
谈谈下一本书。
Talk about the next book.
我觉得自己很勇敢。
I was feeling brave enough.
你还是可以去的。
Well, you can still go.
像这样吗？
Looking like this?
别让他毁了这一切。
Don't let him ruin this for you.
去格林维尔。
Go to Greenville.
好吗，有辆巴士。
Okay? There's a bus.
很简单，跳跃者有时间表。
It's easy. Jumpin's got the schedule.
让他们给你安排个好酒店,
Let them put you up in a nice hotel,
吃一些不用自己做的热腾腾的饭店食物。
eat some hot restaurant food
you didn't have to make.
如果可以的话，再待一周。
Stay a week, if you can.
等你回来我再来看你，好吗？
And I'll come see you
when you're back. Okay?
听听出版商是怎么说的。
Hear how it all went with the publishers.
好吧。
All right.
你冷吗？
Hey, you cold?
我很好，我不需要你照顾我。
I'm fine. I don't need you
to take care of me.
我知道，拿着我的帽子。
I know, but just take my hat.
- 我说了我不需要你的帮助-拿着吧。
- I said I don't need your help.
- Just take it.
能告诉我你的眼睛怎么了吗？
You wanna tell me
what happened to your eye?
我需要写下公共汽车时刻表。
I need to write down the bus schedule.
你有备份吧？
You have a copy, right?
是那个 Chase 对吧？
It was that Chase, wasn't it?
Kya 看着我。
Kya, look at me.
现在你告诉我他做了什么。
Now you tell me what he did.
我说不出口。
I can't say it.
现在都结束了。
It's over now.
我只想让它从我的生活中消失。
I just want it out of my life.
你怎么知道他不会再来找你？
And how you know
he ain't coming after you again?
- 你一个人在外面-请跳下来。
- You're all by your lonesome out there.
- Jumpin', please.
你不能告诉任何人。
You can't tell anybody.
你懂的。
You know how it is.
他们会把我拖进警长办公室逼我向一群男人描述。
They'd drag me into the sheriff's office
and make me describe it to a bunch of men.
然后把我写到报纸上，指控我卖淫。
And then write me up in the papers,
accusing me of whoring.
或者想从他父母那里拿钱。
Or trying to get money out of his parents.
好吗，他们什么都不会做的。
Okay? They'd do nothing about it.
你说得对，Kya。
You're right, Kya.
我不会让事情变得更糟。
And I ain't gonna do anything
to make this thing worse.
但你来来去去的时候告诉我一声。
But you let me know
when you're coming and going.
你听到了吗？
You hear?
我得知道你是不是出城了。
I gotta know if you're out of town.
因为如果我有一段时间见不到你。
'Cause if I don't see you for a while...
谢谢你，跳跃。
Thank you, Jumpin'.
我过几天就要走了。
I'm leaving in a few days.
我一回来就去看你。
I'll come see you as soon as I'm back.
好的，很好。
Okay, that's good.
很好。
That's good.
Miss Price，你能告诉我们10月29日早上你看到了什么吗？
Miss Price, would you tell us
what you saw on the morning of October 29?
我看到了沼泽女孩。
I saw the Marsh Girl...
克拉克小姐，对不起。
Miss Clark, that is. Pardon me.
- 上9点的车-你记性真好。
- Get on the 9:00 bus.
- You've got quite a good memory.
我们都谈过了。
We all talked about it.
我们从没见过她打扮成这样。
We'd never seen her
all cleaned up like that.
梳头，化妆。
Hair combed, makeup.
澄清一下10月29日早上,
Just to be clear,
on the morning of October 29,
你和其他几个人看到克拉克小姐上了早上9点的巴士
you and several others saw
Miss Clark board the 9 a.m. bus
离开巴克利湾。
and leave Barkley Cove.
- 是的，没错-谢谢，Miss Price。
- Yes, that's right.
- Thank you, Miss Price.
没有问题了，法官大人。
No further questions, Your Honor.
Miss Price，Piggly Wiggly 凌晨1:30开门吗？
Miss Price, is the Piggly Wiggly open
at 1:30 in the morning?
没有，长官。
No, sir.
我之所以问是因为,
Well, the reason I ask is,
你不可能看到谁从格林维尔下了夜班车,
you couldn't have seen who got off
the night bus from Greenville,
你也没看见谁上了凌晨两点半的公共汽车
nor could you have seen
who got on the 2:30 a.m. bus
从巴克利湾回到格林维尔，可以吗？
from Barkley Cove
back to Greenville, could you?
没有，当然没有。
Well, no. Of course not.
那天早上你看到克拉克小姐上了去格林维尔的巴士。
So after you saw Miss Clark board
that morning bus to Greenville...
她那晚本可以回巴克利湾的
she could have returned
to Barkley Cove that night
然后回格林维尔吃早餐你都没注意到。
and been back in Greenville for breakfast,
all without you taking notice.
我叫罗伯特 · 福斯特。
My name is Robert Foster.
我是哈里森莫里斯出版公司的高级编辑
I'm a senior editor
at Harrison Morris Publishing Company
在马萨诸塞州的波士顿。
in Boston, Massachusetts.
福斯特先生，晚上7点你和克拉克小姐共进晚餐。
Mr. Foster, you sat down
for dinner with Miss Clark at 7 p.m.
在10月29日晚上。
on the night of October 29.
- 对吗?-是的。
- Correct?
- Yes.
你对她的第一印象是什么？
What was your first impression of her?
我的第一印象是，呃，她非常害羞，非常温柔，非常聪明。
My first impression was, uh, that she was
very shy, very gentle, very smart.
我知道她是个隐士,
I knew that she was something
of a recluse,
但我也知道她是个有天赋的博物学家。
but I also knew
that she was a gifted naturalist.
- 晚餐持续了多久?-至少几个小时。
- How long did that dinner go on?
- At least a few hours.
有些雌性昆虫会吃掉它们的配偶。
Some female insects do eat
their mates.
事实上，萤火虫有两种不同的光信号。
Fireflies, in fact,
have two different light signals.
一个用来交配,
One for mating,
一个是为了吸引雄性，让他成为她的下一餐。
and one to attract a male
in order to make him her next meal.
- 所以她吃了他?-真可怕。
- So she eats him?
- How gruesome.
- 哦，亲爱的-我得少和昆虫呆在一起。
- Oh, dear.
- I must spend less time with insects.
- 太不道德了-确实不道德。
- It's quite amoral.
- Amoral, indeed.
我不知道大自然是否有黑暗的一面。
I don't know
if there is a dark side to nature.
只是创造性的忍耐方式。
Just inventive ways to endure.
再看我一眼。
Against all odds.
第二天早上，也就是10月30日，你和克拉克小姐见面的时候,
And when you met with Miss Clark
the following morning, October 30th,
她的外表和举止有什么异常吗？
was there anything unusual
about her appearance or her demeanor?
完全没有。
Not at all.
没有问题了，法官大人。
No further questions, Your Honor.
福斯特先生，克拉克小姐
Mr. Foster, did Miss Clark stay
跟你和你的同事住在同一家酒店？
at the same hotel
as you and your colleagues?
不，她更喜欢小一点的酒店。
No. She preferred a smaller hotel.
那个，呃，魔山什么的。
The, uh, Mountain something.
你能帮我看看这张格林维尔地图吗？
Could you look at this map
of Greenville for me, please?
我想你会看到皮德蒙特酒店你和你的同事们曾经住过的地方,
I think you'll see The Piedmont,
where you and your colleagues stayed,
然后是克拉克小姐下榻的三山饭店。
and then The Three Mountains Hotel,
where Miss Clark stayed.
你能告诉我哪一家离公共汽车站最近吗？
Could you tell me
which one is closest to the bus station?
三山饭店比较近。
The Three Mountains Hotel is closer.
事实上，三山酒店是最近的酒店
In fact, The Three Mountains is
the closest hotel
去格林维尔汽车站对吗？
to the Greenville bus station.
Is that correct?
看起来是这样。
Looks that way.
没有问题了。
No further questions.
我不认为一个好律师会让他的当事人出庭作证,
I don't think a good lawyer ever puts
their client on the stand,
但这个也许能帮到你。
but this might help you.
让陪审团能够直接听到你的声音。
For the jury to be able
to hear from you, directly.
让他们看到你。
For them to be able to see you...
作为一个真正善良体贴的人。
as the kind
and thoughtful person you truly are.
他们不会看到我那样的。
They're never gonna see me like that.
听着，我知道你有很多理由恨这些人。
Listen. I know you have a world
of reasons to hate these people...
不，我从没恨过他们。
No, I never hated them.
他们恨我。
They hated me.
他们嘲笑我，离开我。
They laughed at me. They left me.
他们骚扰我，袭击我。
They harassed me. They attacked me.
你... 你要我求饶？
You... You want me to beg for my life?
我没有这个能力。
I don't have it in me.
我不会的。
I won't.
我不会自首的。
I will not offer myself up.
他们可以自己做决定。
They can make their decision.
但他们不会对我做任何决定。
But they're not deciding
anything about me.
是他们。
It's them.
他们在评判自己。
They're judging themselves.
那好吧。
All right, then.
米尔顿先生，你一直对我很好。
Mr. Milton,
you have always been kind to me.
即使是小时候。
Even as a child.
我从没忘记过。
I never forgot.
他的生命被那个被抛弃的情人终止了
His life was cut short
by the jilted lover
他无法接受自己回归了。
who could not accept
that he had returned to the fold.
有目击者看到克拉克小姐和蔡斯在沼泽里。
A witness saw Miss Clark
and Chase in the marsh.
听到她说“我要杀了你”
Heard her say the words "I'll kill you."
而且,
And what's more,
那晚有物证把他们联系起来。
is there's physical evidence
from that night connecting them.
她红色羊毛帽上的纤维
Fibers from her red wool cap
留在他的牛仔夹克上。
left on his denim jacket.
爸爸，我过去处理一下。
Dad, I'm going over to deal with it.
还有谁有动机拿走贝壳项链？
Who else would have motive
to take that shell necklace?
你可以，而且你必须,
You can, and you must,
裁定被告谋杀罪名成立。
find that the defendant is guilty
of first-degree murder.
弥尔顿先生。
Mr. Milton.
我一辈子都住在巴克利湾。
I have lived in Barkley Cove
my whole life.
和你一样，我也听过那些荒诞的故事
And like you, I heard the tall tales
告诉我沼泽女孩的事。
told about the Marsh Girl.
她有狼人的血统。
That she was part wolf.
人与猿之间缺失的一环。
A missing link between ape and man.
她的眼睛在黑暗中发光。
That her eyes glowed in the dark.
她来了。
Well, here she is.
事实上，她是个被遗弃的孩子。
The reality is that she was
an abandoned child.
一个小女孩独自在沼泽里生存,
A little girl surviving out there
in the marsh on her own,
受到辱骂和回避。
reviled and shunned.
詹姆斯 · 麦迪逊先生和他的妻子梅布尔,
Mr. James Madison and his wife, Mabel,
他们今天就坐在法庭上。
they are sitting here
in the courtroom today.
他们是镇上唯一关心她的人。
They're about the only people
in this town who showed her any care.
我们其他人..。
The rest of us...
我不好意思说
Well, I'm ashamed to say
我们给她贴上标签，拒绝她因为我们觉得她与众不同。
that we labeled her and rejected her
because we thought she was different.
现在..。
And now...
评判这个害羞又被拒绝的年轻女人的工作
the job of judging this shy
and rejected young woman
都落在了你的肩上。
has fallen on your shoulders.
但你必须根据法庭上陈述的事实做出判断,
But you must base your judgment
on the facts presented in this courtroom,
而不是过去25年的流言和感情。
and not on the rumors and feelings
from the past 25 years.
克拉克小姐有可靠的不在场证明。
Miss Clark has a solid alibi.
Chase Andrews 死的那晚她在格林维尔。
She was in Greenville
the night Chase Andrews died.
到底是什么事实对她不利呢？
And what facts, exactly,
stand against her?
检方尚未证明这起事件确实是谋杀,
The State has not proven
that this incident was indeed a murder,
而不是什么悲惨的意外。
and not just some tragic accident.
控方想让你们相信在晚上11:30,
The State wants you to believe
that at 11:30 at night,
没有一个目击者看到她,
without a single witness seeing her,
她搭上了从格林维尔到巴克利湾的最后一班车,
she caught the last bus
from Greenville to Barkley Cove,
乔装打扮坐上了那辆巴士,
and rode that bus disguised,
因为那晚没有一个司机能认出她
since neither of the bus drivers
that night could identify her
作为一名乘客，一路回到巴克利湾。
as a passenger,
all the way back to Barkley Cove.
然后，不到一个小时..。
And then, in less than an hour...
她在半夜追踪蔡斯 · 安德鲁斯,
she tracks down Chase Andrews
in the middle of the night,
把他引到塔里，杀了他,
lures him to the tower, murders him,
抹去所有物证,
wipes away all physical evidence,
然后不知怎么搭上了凌晨2:30回格林维尔的巴士。
and somehow catches
the 2:30 a.m. bus back to Greenville.
再说一次，没有一个目击者看到她。
Again,
without a single witness seeing her.
做完这一切之后,
And after doing all that,
第二天早上，她平静地会见了她的出版商。
she meets with her publishers
the next morning, unruffled.
这些都不是事实。
Now, these are not facts.
这些只是谣言而已
These are just more of the rumors
还有我们一直在散布的关于克拉克小姐的谣言。
and tall tales that we have been spreading
about Miss Clark her entire life.
我相信你会根据事实做出判断,
I believe you will come
to a judgment based on the facts,
而不是那些你听了很多年的流言蜚语。
and not the gossip
that you have heard for years.
是时候了,
It's time, at last,
为了我们所有人对沼泽女孩公平。
for all of us to be fair
to the Marsh Girl.
也许你应该回家在那里等。
Maybe you should go home
and do your waiting there.
已经六个小时了，你觉得他们还要多久？
Six hours already.
How long do you think they'll take?
希望他们会花很长时间。
Well, let's hope
they take a good long while.
如果陪审员有疑问，我们还有机会。
If a few jurors have doubts,
we got a chance.
陪审团主席，陪审团是否做出了裁决？
Mr. Foreman, is it correct
that the jury has reached a verdict?
是的，法官大人。
We have, Your Honor.
被告请起立宣读判决。
The defendant will please rise
for the reading of the verdict.
站起来。
Stand up.
”我们陪审团认为被告 Catherine Danielle Clark..。
"We, the jury, find the defendant,
Catherine Danielle Clark...
对蔡斯・安德鲁斯先生的谋杀无罪
not guilty of first-degree murder
of Mr. Chase Andrews."
克拉克小姐，你可以走了。
Miss Clark, you are free to go.
我代表州政府为你服刑的时间表示歉意。
And I apologize, on behalf of the State,
for the time that you have served.
本庭解散。
This court is dismissed.
谢谢你。
Thank you.
过来。
Come here.
你没事了，你没事了。
You're okay. You're all right.
别管这些废话了，我们很期待下一本书。
You just forget about this nonsense.
We're looking forward to the next book.
你能送我回家吗？
Can you take me home?
现在我终于可以承认。
Now I can finally admit.
与世隔绝的这几个月渴望回到沼泽地,
All the months in isolation,
yearning to be back in the marsh,
就是知道还有多少东西要去探索,
it was knowing
how much was left to explore,
野外有多少生命等着我们去发现,
how much life to uncover in the wild,
让我坚持下去。
that kept me going.
还有希望,
And the hope,
总是希望..。
always that hope...
希望有一天我能分享它。
that one day I could share it...
和我唯一真正爱过的人在一起。
with the only person
I had ever truly loved.
Kya！
Kya!
Kya.
嘿。
Hey.
你知道我爱你，对吧？
You know I love you, right?
什么？
What?
你能，呃... ? 对不起，对不起。
Will you, uh...? Sorry. I'm sorry.
你愿意嫁给我吗？
Will you marry me?
我是说，你想吗？
I mean, do you want to?
我们不是已经在一起了吗？
Well, aren't we already?
像鹅一样？
Like geese?
我想我可以接受。
I can live with that, I guess.
过来。
Come here.
又来了。
Oh, here we go.
嘿。
Hey.
你好，你好。
Hey, you. Hi, there.
过来，宝贝。
Come here, baby girl.
他那么爱你。
He loved you so much.
Kya 你看。
Kya. Look at that.
你看到那上面了吗? 在树枝的肘部？
You see that up there?
On the elbow of that branch?
我们最后一次见到它们是什么时候？
When's the last time we saw one of those?
我知道。
I know.
这本书很不错，这家伙还在说..。
This book's pretty good.
This guy's still talking about...
我希望当我该离开的时候,
I hope when it is time
for me to leave,
我会很快很轻松地走，不会制造太多的噪音。
I will go quick and easy,
without making too much noise.
妈！
Ma!
妈。
Ma.
Kya？
Kya?
Kya！
Kya!
一直以来，这就足够了。
It has always been enough...
成为自然规律的一部分。
to be part of the natural sequence
of things.
像潮水一样确定。
Sure as the tides.
大自然是我的向导。
Nature my guide.
沼泽知道所有关于死亡的事。
The marsh knows all about death...
并不一定定义为悲剧。
and doesn't necessarily
define it as tragedy.
当然不是罪过。
Certainly not a sin.
它明白每种生物都是为了生存。
It understands that every creature
does what it must to survive.
有时候，为了让猎物活下去。
And that sometimes, for prey to live...
它的捕食者必须死。
its predator must die.
我现在就是沼泽。
I am the marsh now.
我是白鹭的羽毛。
I am the feather of an egret.
我是冲上岸的每一个贝壳。
I am every shell washed upon the shore.
我是一只萤火虫。
I am a firefly.
你会看到数以百计的人向沼泽深处招手。
You'll see hundreds beckoning far
into the dark reaches of the marsh.
你总能在那里找到我。
And that's where you will always find me.
就在那边。
Way out yonder.
小龙虾唱歌的地方。
Where the crawdads sing.